[Music]
the creation and promotion of female
sexual dysfunction as a mental disorder
seems like a textbook case of disease
mongering by the pharmaceutical industry
hearkening back to the first DSM
Psychiatry diagnosis manual which listed
frigidity as a mental disorder along of
course with
homosexuality the latest man man
estation is hypoactive sexual desire
disorder a disease invented by drug
companies it's like when Prozac was
about to go off patent the company
sponsored the creation of a new mental
illness to Market a drug called seraphim
which was simply Prozac repacked in a
pink
capsule the condition previously known
as shyness was branded as social anxiety
disorders so they could get kids on
paxel there are certainly women who are
troubled by low libido but there's no
reliable scientific evidence that
hypoactive sexual desire disorder is a
real medical condition and women can get
diagnosed with it even with a normal
libido a woman highly interested in sex
just not for whatever reason with her
current partner can still qualify for
the diagnosis and the drug even a woman
who is perfectly satisfied with her sex
life may still qualify if her partner
Isn't Our Story begins in 2009 when a
drug company tried to get a failed
anti-depressant called the
fanin approved to treat hypoactive
sexual desire disorder the only problem
it didn't work it was resubmitted again
after more study and was still rejected
as was the appeal but in 2015 the FDA
approved the drug what changed nothing
about its efficacy it didn't work any
better what changed is that the drug
company that bought it helped launch an
AstroTurf fake Grassroots advocacy group
even the score which lobbied for
approval under a feminist
rubric men have their drugs why don't
women get any sex drugs which was
exposed as kind of a bitter irony but
hey within 48 Hours of FDA approval the
drug was sold for a cool billion in cash
very satisfying for the drug company but
what about the women who take the drug
now sold as
Adie not much the drug just doesn't work
as
advertised yes it may stimulate monkeys
to groom each other more but when
researchers dug up the unpublished data
about the drug any clinical benefit was
found to be marginal and the drug was
found to have significant adverse side
effects besides being ineffective it can
be dangerous um combining it with
alcohol can cause dangerous hypotension
and fainting problems so serious that
the FDA put a black box warning on it
its most serious safety alert on the
label that of course no one reads even
without alcohol it can cause severe
drops and blood pressure levels and
cause sudden prolonged
unconsciousness now serious side effects
might be acceptable in some kind of
cancer wonder drug or something but are
entirely unacceptable in a drug given to
healthy women for an invented condition
are there any safe and natural
solutions well there's lots of studies
on diet and men's Sexual Health but what
about women's I've previously explored
the evidence about women with high
cholesterol levels uh reporting
diminished sexual function across a
number of Dimensions this could explain
why a more plant-based diet rich in a
variety of whole plant Foods might be
effective in a Mil ating sexual function
issues in women as it does in men uh
more whole grains beans vegetables and
fruit Less meat deer and sugar
associated with a reduced risk of
erectile
dysfunction because of the anatomy and
physiology of sexual responses are
actually you know quite similar between
the two can have a similar effect you
can you can measure clitoral engorgement
with fancy MRI techniques within minutes
of exposure to an erotic video and we
know now that lubrication is all about
blood flow too within the sexually
aroused vagina it's the hydrostatic
pressure from all the additional pelvic
blood flow that forces fluid to leak out
onto the surface as the vaginal
lubrication so how can we improve blood
flow well the flavonoid phytonutrients
in Cocoa can help open up arteries
increasing pulse wave amplitude from
this set Baseline to this after drinking
cocoa for 4 days uh peing at about 9
minutes after consumption so can that
Valentine's Day chocolate make a
difference uh women who eat chocolate do
tend to have higher female sexual
function index scores but the effect
disappeared once age was taken into
account so despite all the potential
biological mechanisms supporting a role
for chocolate as an afrodesiac food the
study failed to show a benefit one would
assume that chocolate could improve
blood flow per remember that was with
cocoa powder maybe the fat and sugar and
chocolate is counteracting the
benefits what are some whole food
sources of flavonoids well onions have a
lot and indeed fresh onion juice
enhances copulatory behavior in rats but
for those of us less interested in
increasing the percentage of ejaculating
rats and looking for something other
than onion juice for a hot date how
about that at
Apple but there wasn't a study
addressing the potential correlation
between Daily Apple consumption and
women's sexual function
until
now the title kind of gives it away but
women were split into regular Daily
Apple consumers versus those consuming
less than an apple a day and the
hundreds of Apple eaters in the study
scored significantly higher on the
female sexual function
index now note they only includ Ed women
eating unpeeled apples because the
phytonutrients are concentrated in the
peel so we don't know if there's a link
with peeled apples and this was just an
observational study so further studies
will be necessary to clarify the
relationship between apple intake and
female sexuality however the present
data can allow the development of future
research for identifying new compounds
and food supplements to use in female
sexuality recovery uh or you can just
try
eating an apple
[Music]